

Junior Front End Developer HTML/CSS/React

Contact

Tel: 07467 080577 LinkedIn: View Profile

Email: bougault.stevens@gmail.com

Portfolio: View my work

City: Leeds

Work Locations

Leeds, Sheffield, Wakefield, Bradford, Huddersfield, Halifax, Manchester, York, Harrogate

Professional Development

Udemy - The complete 2021 Web Development Bootcamp

MongoDB and more (currently studying)

Udemy - iOS 13 & Swift 5 The complete iOS App Development Bootcamp

Education

2006 -2008 CAP Cuisine (Professional Certificate)

Strasbourg, Centre de Formation (Centre European de Formation et de Promotion)

Interests

Technology, languages, travel, films, Paris Saint-germain and training

About Me

I'm a Front-End Developer with a knack for blending creativity and technology. A native of France, I moved to England ten years ago, motivated by ambitious goals. My first professional journey took me to Michelin-starred kitchens, where I developed a fine-tuned sense of artistry and discipline. Eager for a new challenge, I pivoted to technology and secured a role as a junior software engineer. In this position, I managed databases and implemented new features. However, I found myself missing the creative freedom I had in my culinary career. Now, I'm excited to bring my artistic perspective to web development. As someone who is largely self-taught, I am constantly seeking new learning opportunities, and committed to delivering exceptional work in any field I choose to pursue.

Read about my journey and view my portfolio https://stevensbougault.co.uk/

Employment History

August 2021 – July 2023

Junior Software Engineer - Tribal Group

- Developed software using Uniface and Javascript
- Managed databses using SQL, including design tables, creating and executing queries, and integrating database solution into software applications
- Conducting manual unit testing on the Uniface applications to ensure their quality and functionality
- Gained strong understanding of Agile methodologies, particularly Scrum through active participation in daily meetings and contributions to the entire development cycle

Sept 2020 - Now

Personal Development - Self study and building my Portfolio

Completed online bootcamps where I have learnt tech skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery and I am now moving onto React. I built my first and second (improved) portfolio that I continue to add projects to.

Dec 2016 - Nov 2020

Contract Chef

Various 3 and 4 Rosettes Restaurants and Hotels (ongoing work on different assignments)

- Innovative menu planning and design
- Training and development of staff
- Ordering and controlling food stocks within budgets



Employment History - Cont...

Dec 2019 - July 2020

Development Chef, Solina - Elland, Leeds

- Developing a variety of recipes for major supermarkets and their suppliers
- Recipe sample management

April 2016 - Nov 2016

Head Chef/Development Chef, Filmore and Union, Leeds

- Solely responsible for managing the kitchen including managing food orders, portion size, monitoring expenditure and stock control
- Developing new menus and dishes at the central kitchen dishes for all the restaurants of the company.
- Organising special events

May 2014 - July 2015

Pastry Chef, The Man Behind The Curtain, Leeds

- Pastry chef at Michael O'Hare's fine dining restaurant offering 11 course degustation set menu
- Creating and presenting dishes to diners in the restaurant and providing an excellent service and rapport
- Solely responsible for managing the pastry section including managing food orders, portion size, monitoring expenditure and stock control in addition to ensuring timely completion of dishes

March 2013 - Aug 2013

Working holiday Visa: New Zealand

April 2012 - March 2013

Working holiday Visa: Australia

Mar 2011 - Mar 2012

Chef de Partie

The Majestic Hotel - Barceló hotel chain, Harrogate

Mar 2011 - Mar 2012

Commis Chef

Maison de L'Esperance, Nantes, France

Sept 2009 - Feb 2011

Soldier

French Army - GAP (4 regiment de chasseurs), France